The science is clear, the future is not.
Before the Flood is a documentary film directed by Fisher Stevens.
A look at how climate change affects our environment and what society can do to prevent the
demise of endangered species, ecosystems, and native communities across the planet.
Self, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Self, played by Bill Clinton.
Self, played by John Kerry.
Self, played by Barack Obama.
Self, played by Elon Musk.
Self, played by Pope Francis.
Before the Flood is a 2016 documentary film about
climate change directed by Fisher Stevens.
The film was produced as a collaboration between Stevens, Leonardo DiCaprio, James
Packer, Brett Ratner, Trevor Davidoski, and Jennifer Davisson Killoran.
Martin Scorsese is an executive producer.
The film covers effects of climate change in various regions of
the world, and discusses climate change denial.
Numerous public figures are interviewed in the documentary.
To offset the carbon emissions of the production, the
filmmakers paid a voluntary carbon tax.
The soundtrack features compositions by Trent Reznor and
Atticus Ross, Mogwai and Gustavo Santaolalla.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival in September 2016, and was released
theatrically on October 21, before airing on the National Geographic Channel on October 30.
As part of National Geographic's commitment to covering climate change, the
documentary was made widely available and free of charge on various platforms.
It received generally positive critical reviews.
The film explores themes of society, climate change,
natural disaster, global warming, green energy.